shadows.com 2007-10-14

# Privacy Policy - Shadows

**Effective: December 7, 2005 Previous Update: July 12, 2005**

At Shadows, we strive to develop innovative services to better serve our users. We recognize that privacy is an important issue, so we design and operate our services with the protection of your privacy in mind. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of personal information we gather, as well as the steps we take to safeguard it. 

**What this Privacy Policy covers:**

  * This Privacy Policy pertains to the use of the Shadows web site at http://www.shadows.com/ 
  * This Privacy Policy covers how Shadows treats personal information that Shadows collects and receives. Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number.

_**Information We Collect**_

"Personal Information" is information that individually identifies you, such as your first and last name, physical address or email address. 

  * We ask for your email address when you create an account with us ("Account Information"). We use that information to provide Shadows' services. 
  * You can provide personal information such as your website or blog address and a profile about yourself. You do not have to provide this information in order to obtain a Shadows user account.
  * Shadows automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, the date and time of your query, browser type, cookie information, and the page you request. We use this information to operate, develop and improve our services.
  * Some of our services do not require personal information such as Shadows search, the Shadows Toolbar and viewing Shadow pages.

_**How We Use Your Information**_

Shadows uses your personal information for the following general purposes: To provide you with our products and services, to allow for your identification and authentication onto our site, to contact you for administrative functions, and for internal research and reporting purposes. 

We may send you communications relating to the Shadows service, such as service announcements, technical updates and administrative messages that are considered part of your Shadows account. If you do not wish to receive certain communications such as newsletters, you can check the appropriate box on your user profile page. 

_IP Addresses_

IP Addresses are automatically reported by your browser each time you view a Shadows web page. Your IP address is stored in our user registration databases when you register with Shadows. IP addresses may be used for various purposes, including: 

  * To diagnose or service technology problems reported by our users or engineers. 
  * To tailor advertising based on geographic area or other information derived from your IP address. 
  * To estimate the total number of users visiting Shadows from specific geographical regions. 
  * To make sure that people are not voting for themselves or friends during contests or promotions.

_Cookies_

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. If you reject all cookies, you will not be able to use Shadows products or services that require you to "sign in," and you may not be able to take full advantage of the Shadows service. Shadows uses cookies for a number of purposes, including to:

  * Access your information when you "sign in".
  * Keep track of preferences you specify while you are using Shadows' services.
  * Display the most appropriate advertising banners, based on your interests and activity on Shadows. 
  * Estimate and report our total audience size and traffic. 
  * Conduct research to improve Shadows' content and services.
  * Measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use our site.

If you do not want your visits to Shadows logged, you can "opt-out" of our ability to analyze your data by configuring your browser to reject cookies. 

_**Sharing your Information**_

Shadows does not rent, sell or share your personal information with non-affiliated third parties for their direct marketing purposes without your consent. However, by using Shadows you consent to certain situations where personal information may be disclosed, including: 

  * To help analyze and optimize our online traffic. We use third party service providers to measure how our website is being used, the effectiveness of advertising and to perform technical functions. No personal information of our users is shared, rather only information such as what links are clicked, what topics are most popular and what pages are viewed. We control how this data may and may not be used by our partners.
  * To fulfill our legal obligations in complying with court orders or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.
  * To investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities, including without limitation, fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Shadows' terms of use, or as otherwise permitted or required by law.
  * Shadows may share demographic information with business partners, but only in an aggregate form.
  * Shadows displays targeted advertisements based on personal information that is exhibited in people's profiles. Shadows primarily uses other companies (such as Google) to display these advertisements on some of our pages set and they set and access their own cookies on your computer. Other entities' use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Advertisers or other entities do not have access to Shadows' cookies. 
  * If Shadows should ever file for bankruptcy or merge with another company, or if Shadows should decide to buy, sell or reorganize some part or all of its business, Shadows may be required to disclose your personal information to prospective or actual purchasers or receive personal information from sellers. It is Shadows's practice to seek appropriate protection for information disclosed or received in these types of transactions but Shadows may have no control over this process and in such event your personal information may be transferred like any other asset of the company.

_Disclosures over which Shadows has no control_

You should be aware that in some cases Shadows has no control over the information about you that may be disclosed to the public. For example: 

  * When you post a message, complete your Shadows user profile or share links, your Shadows ID or alias that you are posting under is visible to other users. If you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. It is your choice to decide how much personal information you post online. 
  * The sites displayed as search results or linked to by Shadows' services are developed by people over whom Shadows exercises no control. These other sites may place their own cookies on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and cannot control the activities of, those other advertisers or websites.

_**Information Relating to Children**_

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA") generally requires that we inform parents and legal guardians about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information from children under 13 years of age before collecting such information. Shadows is not directed at children under 13 years of age. We will not knowingly collect personal information of children under 13 years of age, and if we learn that we have inadvertently collected such information, we will promptly delete it. 

Parents, the following are some resources that may help you in monitoring and limiting your childrens' access to certain types of material on the Internet. While Shadows does not endorse these products, we provide information about them as a public service to our users. 

  * Control Kids - [http://www.controlkids.com](http://www.controlkids.com/)
  * Cyber Sitter - [http://www.solidoak.com](http://www.solidoak.com/)
  * Net Nanny - [http://www.netnanny.com](http://www.netnanny.com/)

_**Editing and Deleting Account Information**_

You can change your Shadows Account Information, at any time by logging into your user profile page. You can request to delete your Shadows account at any time by sending an account deletion request to [support@shadows.com](mailto:support@shadows.com) **.** However, please note that your identification, billing and contact information may remain in Shadows' records for some period. 

_**International Visitors**_

This web site is hosted in the United States and is intended for United States visitors. If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States and by providing your personal data you consent to that transfer. 

_**Security of your Personal Information**_

We take the security of your Personal Information seriously. We limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs. Our service providers and agents are required to maintain client confidentiality, and may not use the information for any unauthorized purpose. Your Shadows Account Information is password-protected. In certain areas, Shadows uses SSL-encryption to protect data transmissions. 

Though Shadows uses these safeguards, no data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make reasonable efforts to ensure security on our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our safeguards. 

If Shadows learns of a security systems breach we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using this web site, or providing personal information to us through any means, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of this site. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us at privacy@shadows.com. 

_**Changes to this Privacy Policy**_

Shadows may update this policy at any time for any reason. Changes will be indicated by a change to the effective date at the start of the policy. In general, we will only use your personal information in the manner described in the Privacy Policy in effect when we received the personal information you provided. If there are any material changes that would cause us to use your personal information in a way that is less restrictive than that disclosed in the policy at the time we received your personal information, we will undertake to provide notice and obtain your consent prior to implementing such changes. 

_**Contacting us**_

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or suggestions please e-mail us at [shadows@pluck.com](mailto:shadows@pluck.com) or you can contact us at:

Shadows, c/o Pluck Corporation  
720 Brazos Street, Suite 900  
Austin, TX 78701
